hello everyone
good morning
my name is rambadra
and i am working as a trainer in hdfc
life for the wizard
today i want to discuss a
topic that will be very helpful for your
life that which adds some value to your
life
for example
we prefer to eat burger while comparing
to one is it right
yes
because
there are some extra added ingredients
in between the bun two buns
which will looks attractive
and brings a great taste to the basic
parts
that's true correct
in the same way
we prefer to eat a sandy ice cream while
comparing the plain vanilla ice cream
because of this
extra added ingredients like
fruits and
nuts
and the flour
because all this together looks more
attractive
and brings a great taste to the food
it means
the ingredients what we are adding
it looks attractive
and it brings a great taste to the basic
eatables is that true
yes
now if you are talking about the
insurance policies
some of the policies will have
the maturity benefit and some of the
policies will have the death benefit
and some of the policies will have both
both the benefits but
they don't look much lucrative
because they are not getting any
additional benefits
they are not getting any additional
benefits
there is a concept called
riders
if we add rider to the basic plan
we can add some more extra benefits
and supplementing the existing benefits
of this basic plan that concept is
called
rider
today i wanted to discuss about the
riders with you
what is a rider
what are the advantages of rider and how
many types of riders are there in
in our organization
okay
rider
is an a rider is having a ba some issue
which is
equal to
or less than the basic summation
a writer is having a submission which is
less than or equal to the basic
summation of the plan
it will be having a benefits like
by taking a rider customer will be
having a benefits like for the
disability
critical illness
and accidental that benefit
those kind of benefits
will be getting for the customer by
adding these riders
we have three riders in our organization
one
critical investigator
two
product plus rider
three
income benefit on accidental disability
writer
now i wanted to discuss about the
critical investigator what is critical
investigator and how it is getting
profitable and what are the advantages
for the customer by having a
critical investigator
now let us take an example
if a customer is having a basic term
plan
for the live coverage
will he getting any additional benefit
for that
definitely
not
if the same customer is suffering with
the critical illness like cancer will he
getting any benefit from this plan
no absolutely no
exactly
what if the same customer
is getting a benefit with the same
documentation
with the same medicals in occurring for
the customer really getting benefited
for this
definitely yes definitely customer will
getting benefited out of this
now
customer can take a critical interest
rider with the base plan
critical lineage writer will be covering
the predefined 19 critical illness
listed critical illness if the customer
is suffering
if the customer is identified
by suffering any of this listed 19
critical illness
as we discussed
rider will having a submission which is
equal to or less than the basic sum
issue
for that
customer has to pay
a premium
which may be
less than or equal to 30 percent of the
basic sum issued
for that customer is getting a
benefit customer
is identified if the customer is
identified any one of the 19 listed
critical illness
from the date of the diagnosed if the
customer survives for the next 30 days
then the riders submission will be
payable for the
customer
rider some issue will be payable for the
customer and the rider will get
terminated
and the basic plan what the customer is
having about for his life that will be
continued
what happening in this situation
customer is getting the benefit of this
19 criticalness which is listed out
if you get if we get uh suffered any one
of this 19 critical unless you will
getting a ride writer some issue without
any extra documentation without any
extra medicals
without having any extra efforts
customer is getting a benefit of this
what happens to
the organization what happens what is
the benefit getting for the organization
and the employee of the organization
it is like a complete win-win situation
customer is getting benefit from the
rider as well as
the distribution channel is also getting
the
some commission
and if you are talking about the fls
and he is also getting some sales
credits
and the company company is also getting
an additional premium for the from the
customer so all the way everyone is
getting benefited from this
riders not only customer the
distribution channel
and the fls and the company
too
so
this is the advantage of the critical
illness writer
thank you